<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>calculus2 on 思｜制 - Thinking, lecturing and making</title>
    <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/tags/calculus2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in calculus2 on 思｜制 - Thinking, lecturing and making</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 11:32:36 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tigertooth4.github.io/tags/calculus2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>W16-Extra1 Convergence of Taylor Series; Error Estimates</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w16extra-convergence-of-taylor-series-error-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 11:32:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w16extra-convergence-of-taylor-series-error-estimates/</guid>
      <description>周次: 16 日期: June 9, 2022 节次: Extra1 In this lecture, we estimate the error of Taylor polynomial to the generating function. The result provides a criteria for the convergence of Taylor series. A lot of common functions can be expanded to Taylor series according to this result. And without the proof, we will see that more common functions can be represented by power</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W16-S1 Taylor Series and Maclaurin Series</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w16s1-taylor-and-maclaurin-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 12:28:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w16s1-taylor-and-maclaurin-series/</guid>
      <description>周次: 16 日期: June 8, 2022 节次: 1 In this lecture, we show that the convergent power series represents a function $f(x)$. The coefficient of the power series can be presented in turn by the function. This opens a new page for the application of power series, for we can associate power series to any infinitely differentiable functions. To see the power series derived</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W14-S2 Absolute and Conditional Convergence, Power Series</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w14s2-absolute-conditional-convergence-power-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 17:51:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w14s2-absolute-conditional-convergence-power-series/</guid>
      <description>周次: 14 日期: May 27, 2022 节次: 2 In this lecture, we will continue the discussion of absolute and conditional convergence, give the absolute convergence test to show any absolutely convergent series itself must converge. We also look at the difference between absolute and conditional convergences by showing that an absolute convergent series remains the same even after the rearrangement of the terms. However,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W14-S1 The Root Test, Alternating Series, Absolute and Conditional Convergence</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w14s1-the-root-test-alternating-series-absolute-and-conditional-convergences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 16:19:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w14s1-the-root-test-alternating-series-absolute-and-conditional-convergences/</guid>
      <description>周次: 14 日期: May 25, 2022 节次: 1 In this lecture, we continue the discussion on the root test (for the series with non-negative terms). And we discuss alternating series, there’s a test called Leibniz’s or alternating series test. Alternating series converges in a manner that positive and negative terms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W13-S1 The Integral Test and Comparison Tests</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w13s1-integral-test-and-comparison-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 16:45:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w13s1-integral-test-and-comparison-tests/</guid>
      <description>周次: 13 日期: May 18, 2022 节次: 1 In this lecture, we develop some convergence tests for the series with non-negative terms. These are the Integral Test and Comparison Tests. Both tests are based on the Monotonic Bounded Theorem for partial sum sequences. Before developing the tests, we will recap the previous section first. I. Recap: § 11.2 Series Basic Problems for Series Primarily,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W12-S2 Series</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w12s2-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:20:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w12s2-series/</guid>
      <description>周次: 12 日期: May 13, 2022 节次: 2 In this lecture, we will talk about series, we introduce the sigma notation, and utilize limit to define the sum of a series. Primarily, there are two types of series whose sums can be found directly, by definition. Those are called Geometric Series and Telescoping Series. To study a divergent series, we introduce the $n$th term</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W1-S2 Volumes by Slicing (cont.) , Volumes by Cylindrical Shells</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w1s2-volume-by-cylindrical-shells/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 21:44:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w1s2-volume-by-cylindrical-shells/</guid>
      <description>周次: 1 日期: February 25, 2022 节次: 2 Outline For solids of revolution, the volume is relatively easy to find out. In section 6.1 and 6.2, we developed three method for finding volumes. The first two are based on the area of cross-sections, therefore these cases are direct applications of the formula $V = \int_a^b A(x) dx.$ The third case uses cylindrical shells for</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W1s1 Volume by Slicing</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w1s1-volume-by-slicing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 12:36:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w1s1-volume-by-slicing/</guid>
      <description>W1-S1 Volumes by Slicing and Rotation About an Axis 周次: 1 日期: February 23, 2022 节次: 1 In this semester, we will be beginning with the applications of definite integrals. Today’s course is the contents in section 6.1 (Volumes by Slicing and Rotation About an Axis). Outline Review: Riemann sums &amp;amp; Definite Integral Definite integral is dealing with</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
