<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>lecture on 思｜制 - Thinking, lecturing and making</title>
    <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/tags/lecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lecture on 思｜制 - Thinking, lecturing and making</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 16:22:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tigertooth4.github.io/tags/lecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>W8-§1 Improper Integrals</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w8s1-improper-integrals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 16:22:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w8s1-improper-integrals/</guid>
      <description>周次: 8 备注: Attendance check 日期: April 13, 2022 节次: 1 In this lecture, we consider integrals when the domain of integration is infinite, or the range of the integrand is infinite. Such cases are not Riemann integrable, therefore, they are called improper integrals. We would like to manage the integrations for these cases, via some limit procedure. Outline Improper Integrals of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W7-S2 Numerical Integration</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w7s2-numerical-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 14:47:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w7s2-numerical-integration/</guid>
      <description>周次: 7 备注: Attendance check 日期: April 8, 2022 节次: 2 In this lecture, we will take a quick glance at the Numerical Integration methods. Numerical integrations are very useful in practice. The methods we are going to learn are Trapezoidal Method and Simpson’s Method. We will learn how to evaluate an integration numerically,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W6-S2 Integration of Rational Functions and Trigonometric Integrals</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w6s2-integration-of-rational-functions-and-trigonometric-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 11:42:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w6s2-integration-of-rational-functions-and-trigonometric-integration/</guid>
      <description>周次: 6 日期: April 1, 2022 节次: 2 In this lecture, we continue presenting the integration of rational functions. After finishing this part, we are going to discuss some trigonometric integration techniques. Outline § 8.3 Integration of Rational Functions Method of Partial Fractions ( for $f(x)/g(x)$ Proper) Factorize the denominator $g(x)$, obtain all its linear and quadratic factors, as well as their powers. In</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W6-S1 Integration by Parts and Integration of Rational Functions</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w6s1-integration-by-parts-integration-of-rational-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 14:07:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w6s1-integration-by-parts-integration-of-rational-functions/</guid>
      <description>周次: 6 日期: March 30, 2022 节次: 1 In this lecture, we’ll learn a new technique for integration, called Integration by Parts. The second part of the lecture will be devoted to the partial fractions decomposition of rational functions. By using such technique, we are able to integrate all the rational functions! § 8.2 Integration by Parts Integration by parts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W5-S2 Integration Techniques</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w5s2-integration-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 11:20:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w5s2-integration-techniques/</guid>
      <description>周次: 5 日期: March 25, 2022 节次: 2 In this course, we will discuss the definition of hyperbolic functions. And we shift our attention to several integration techniques. These techniques can help us integrate more functions. A typical technique called “Integration by Parts” will be discussed as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W4-S2 Transcendental Functions (2)</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w4s2-transcendental-functions-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 12:26:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w4s2-transcendental-functions-2/</guid>
      <description>周次: 4 备注: Attendance check 日期: March 18, 2022 节次: 2 In this lecture, we continue on the discussion of logarithmic and exponential functions. The simplest differential equation is discussed, there are a lot of real applications even for such simple equations. And the definitions of growth rates are given in terms of the notation “big-oh</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W4-S1 Transcendental Functions</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w4s1-transcendental-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 16:44:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w4s1-transcendental-functions/</guid>
      <description>周次: 4 日期: March 16, 2022 节次: 1 In this and next lectures, we will quickly go through the contents in chapter 7. Since a lot of the contents have been taught last semester or have known in high school age. § 7.1 Inverse Functions and Their Derivatives We have learned inverse functions, their domain and range, their graph, etc. In particular, we have</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W3-S2 Work, Fluid Pressure and Forces</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w3s2-work-fluid-pressure-force/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 13:24:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w3s2-work-fluid-pressure-force/</guid>
      <description>周次: 3 日期: March 11, 2022 节次: 2 In this lecture, we’ll give a brief introduction to the concepts of works and fluid pressures. Many examples will be presented. This lecture covers §6.6 and §6.7. Outline Work Work refers specifically to a force acting on a body and the body</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W3-S1 Areas of Surfaces of Revolution and the Theorem of Pappus</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w3s1-area-of-surface-or-revolution-theorems-of-pappus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:16:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w3s1-area-of-surface-or-revolution-theorems-of-pappus/</guid>
      <description>周次: 3 日期: March 9, 2022 节次: 1 A curve sweeps out a surface in the space around is called a surface of revolution. The “area” of this surface depends on the length of the rope and the distance of each of its segments from the axis of revolution. In this section, we calculate the area of surface of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W2-S2 Moments and Center of Masses</title>
      <link>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w2s2-moments-and-center-of-masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:33:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tigertooth4.github.io/post/2022-calculus2/w2s2-moments-and-center-of-masses/</guid>
      <description>周次: 2 日期: March 4, 2022 节次: 2 Outline In this lecture, we discuss moments ( 质量矩）and centers of mass. Two concepts are related. In this lecture, we only deal with one- and two-dimensional problems (Essentially all the problems been dealt with are in one-dimension). Basic Principle for Center of Mass and Moment Definition. (Center of Mass) For</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
